[
    {
        "question": "Frederiksborg Castle is located in which country?",
        "answer": "Denmark -- The castle occupies three islets in Castle Lake just north of Copenhagen. It was built between 1600 and 1620."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a narrow strip of land that connects two larger landmasses and separates two bodies of water?",
        "answer": "Isthmus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which animal is paraded through Gstaad, Switzerland at the end of summer?",
        "answer": "Cows -- Farmers dress their cows up with bells and flower crowns for the walk through town. The tradition started in 2014."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find the magnificent temple Wat Tham Suea also known as `Tiger Cave Temple`?",
        "answer": "Thailand -- The name Tiger Cave Temple comes from the tiger paw prints that are found in one of the caves in the area."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has a fast food restaurant called Mash Donald`s?",
        "answer": "Iran -- It is a loving tribute to McDonald`s, serving halal burgers, crispy chicken nuggets, and French fries to customers."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which beloved Parisian landmark was intended to be temporary?",
        "answer": "Eiffel Tower -- Plans to demolish it in 1909 were abandoned when city officials recognized its value as a radiotelegraph station."
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Tahoe straddles the border of which states?",
        "answer": "California and Nevada -- Located in the Sierra Mountains, its name is derived from the Washoe word `tahoe,` which means `big water.`"
    },
    {
        "question": "Besides `monster` sightings, Loch Ness is also known as the U.K.`s what?",
        "answer": "Largest lake by volume -- The depths reach to almost 800 feet; so, it doesn`t freeze during the winter despite the bitter cold of the Scottish Highlands."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city will you find Michaelangelo`s secret underground drawings?",
        "answer": "Florence -- In 1530, he stayed in a hidden room beneath the Basilica di San Lorenzo where he continued is art work."
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is New Zealand`s Ninety Mile Beach?",
        "answer": "55 miles"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what month does Russia celebrate the October Revolution?",
        "answer": "November"
    },
    {
        "question": "Minnesota, it is illegal to be what in bed?",
        "answer": "Naked"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Denmark, what is a Svangerskabsforebyggendemiddel?",
        "answer": "A condom"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the first U.S. state to ban billboards?",
        "answer": "Hawaii -- Billboards were banned in Hawaii in 1927."
    },
    {
        "question": "In which Californian city can you find the Coronado Bridge?",
        "answer": "San Diego -- The bridge crosses the San Diego Bay to connect the city of Coronado to downtown San Diego."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is Europe`s most powerful waterfall?",
        "answer": "Iceland (Dettifoss Waterfall) -- More than 96,500 gallons of water drops 150 feet into the surrounding canyon every second."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the only sovereign monarchy in Oceania?",
        "answer": "Tonga -- Although Tonga has its own sovereign monarch, the country is also a member of the British Commonwealth."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only U.S. state that borders an ocean and a Great Lake?",
        "answer": "New York -- It borders Lake Ontario, Lake Erie and meets the Atlantic Ocean."
    },
    {
        "question": "What line is located at 0 degrees longitude?",
        "answer": "Prime meridian -- Running through Greenwich, England, it is the line that separates Earth`s Eastern and Western Hemispheres."
    },
    {
        "question": "The Northern Hemisphere is home to 90% of the world`s what?",
        "answer": "People -- It is likely due to the fact that North America, Europe, and parts of Asia and Africa are all located above the equator."
    },
    {
        "question": "What country has the world`s shortest coastline?",
        "answer": "Monaco -- It has a mere 2.5 miles of coastline along a world-famous section of the Mediterranean called the French Riviera."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the official currency of Russia?",
        "answer": "Ruble -- The Russian ruble (abbreviated as RUB) has been used as the country`s currency since the 13th century \u2014 making it the second oldest currency still in use, after the British pound sterling."
    },
    {
        "question": "From which mountain in the U.S. can you see the most states?",
        "answer": "Lookout Mountain, Georgia -- One can see seven states from the top on a clear day -- Tennessee, Alabama, South Carolina, North Carolina, Virginia, Kentucky and Georgia."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which U.S. state is home to the world`s largest convenience store?",
        "answer": "Texas -- Buc-ee`s in New Braunfels has 67,000 square feet of retail space \u2014 about 22 average-sized 7-Eleven stores \u2014 and 1,000 parking spaces."
    },
    {
        "question": "What river separates New Hampshire and Vermont?",
        "answer": "Connecticut River"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of New Mexico?",
        "answer": "Santa Fe"
    },
    {
        "question": "What city in New Mexico was named after the Spanish words `the crosses`?",
        "answer": "Las Cruces"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which New England state does not have any ocean coastline?",
        "answer": "Vermont"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state has the most shoreline along the Pacific Ocean?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US city is home to Franklin Mountains State Park?",
        "answer": "El Paso"
    },
    {
        "question": "The deepest lake in the world, Lake Baikal, is in which region of Russia?",
        "answer": "Siberia -- The oldest freshwater lake in the world, dating back 20-25 million years, Lake Baikal is home to the world`s only true freshwater seal species, aptly named Baikal seals."
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Victoria is the largest lake in Africa and has roughly 1,000 what?",
        "answer": "Islands -- Spanning 26,600 square miles, Lake Victoria contains approximately 1,000 Islands, ranging from tiny dots of land to larger inhabited islands."
    },
    {
        "question": "Lake Titicaca is said to be the birthplace of which ancient civilization?",
        "answer": "Incan -- Located on the border of present-day Peru and Bolivia, Lake Titicaca was a sacred space to the Incan people."
    },
    {
        "question": "Bammy is a traditional Jamaican bread made primarily of what?",
        "answer": "Cassava flour"
    },
    {
        "question": "In England, the victim of an April Fool`s joke is sometimes popularly referred to as what?",
        "answer": "A noodle -- Victims of April Fool`s pranks in England may also be called a `gob`, `gobby` or `noddy`."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the world`s longest golf course?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What African ethnic group is known as `the people of the veil` because the men wear veils that conceal all but their eyes?",
        "answer": "Tuareg"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where can you find the Petronas Towers?",
        "answer": "Kuala Lumpur"
    },
    {
        "question": "Queen Alexandra`s father and brother were kings of what country?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state has Cheyenne as its capital city?",
        "answer": "Wyoming"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city is served by Schwechat airport?",
        "answer": "Vienna"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ocean is the world`s largest ocean?",
        "answer": "Pacific Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did Afghanistan gain its independence from the United Kingdom?",
        "answer": "1919"
    },
    {
        "question": "What desert surrounds Las Vegas?",
        "answer": "The Mojave Desert"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the world`s northernmost capital city?",
        "answer": "Reykjavik"
    },
    {
        "question": "What sea does the Danube empty into?",
        "answer": "The Black Sea"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which major city was once known as Byzantium?",
        "answer": "Istanbul"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has a presidential office known as `the Pink House`?",
        "answer": "Argentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the natural gas-burning `Fire Mountain` located?",
        "answer": "Azerbaijan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are the Admiralty Islands?",
        "answer": "Papua New Guinea"
    }
]